Now in this lecture, I'm going to show you quickly through the console, all the attributes
that we discussed on the foundation model selection strategy.
So the first one is the modality.
So if I just go to the little console, so I'm on the AWS bedrock service.
And now let me just click on this model catalog.
Let me just click on this serverless and let me just move to this to the left.
And if I just click here, so here you'll be able to see the modality of all the foundation
models.
We have the foundation model name here.
So we have plot and then we have anthropic, the provider name, and if I just continue to
scroll right, you'll be able to see the modality.
So you can see a text vision.
So text vision is basically multimodal.
Then you have some models which are text.
And if I just go to the left, you'll be able to see here, plot 3.5, is just text, which means
it will only accept text input.
And this can accept both text and image input.
And if I just continue to scroll down, you'll be able to see embedding here, speech, image
and so on.
Now if I just go to the next one, you'll be able to see the task complexity.
So for the task complexity, what you can do is you can just read through the attributes
of each model on what are the areas it focuses on.
So here for this model, we have hybrid reasoning, extended thinking.
And let me just click on this model and you'll be able to see more detail.
So here you can see the next generation anthropic, most intelligent model, plot 4.5, is
an industry leading across coding agents, computer use, enterprise workflows.
And then it just talks about some of the use cases.
So it's good for coding and then there are some other use cases.
Then if I just continue to scroll down, so categories, these are the categories, it excels
in.
For each model, you'll be able to see the key use cases.
Now there is second aspect to it.
So let's take a look at these models from LAMA.
So you'll be able to see a LAMA4 Maverick 17B instruct.
So 17B means number of billion parameters it has.
So it has 17 billion parameters.
Then there could be other models.
So you have LAMA 3.2, 11 billion and then there is one on 3 billion.
So you and then there is one on 90 billion, 70 billion.
So usually if there are more number of parameters than that means that particular model
can handle more complex tasks.
So for anthropic and open A, they don't actually publish the number of model parameters.
It could be in billions and trillions.
But in general, most of the foundation model would provide what is the number of model parameters.
And as we discussed earlier, if it's less than 8 billion, it's a small language model,
otherwise a large language model.
So based on the number of model parameters and the key strengths highlighted here, you
can make a decision on the right foundation model.
Next if I just go to the context window, so you'll be able to see the context window
for most models.
So here is the max token.
It's the maximum size of input it can take.
So if I just scroll up, so these are all anthropic models.
And if I just scroll on left, you can see these are all anthropic models.
And they usually have, they have max token size or context window 200K can see all this.
And then there are smaller ones as well, 8K.
And if I just scroll down, they would mostly be for models from meta.
So next we have guardrail and safety.
And we already discussed earlier, so if I just go back, if I just go on the left-hand side,
you can go here to chat and text playground select the model here.
And then just apply.
And then you can provide maybe toxic input and see if it is responding to the toxic
input.
So you'll have to try this out a little bit, okay.
Then next we have quality and accuracy of output.
Again, you'll have to try out the models based on your use case.
And then what you can do is you can just go here assess evaluations.
So you can use this bedrock evaluation service to evaluate the output of different models
and then make the right choice.
Next we have cost predictability and token efficiency.
So now if I just go to the cost page and if I just go here, so I'm on the Amazon bedrock
pricing page, here you can see the pricing for different foundation models.
So here we have the meta llama and here it is the 70 billion parameter.
So you can see the price per token is 0.0072.
And if I just take another model, let's say this llama 3.2 11B and the price is much lower.
So this llama 3.3 instruct 70B is almost 4.5 times the price of this 11 billion parameter
model.
And then if we just go up and select some other models, so let's say from anthropic and
you can see here price per 1000 tokens, it's even more expensive.
So based on the cost per API request, so you will have to see what is the right foundation
model for your use case.
Then you also have regional availability and quotas.
So not all the foundation models are available across all AWS regions.
Some of the models might not be available in particular regions.
So you will have to evaluate whether that model is available in your region.
Then you also have something known as quotas and we'll just get to that in a little bit.
Let's see, I think we already discussed there are some latency optimize inference models,
which we'll discuss a little later.
Then the next thing I just want to show is the language support.
So if I just go back to the console and if I just go to the model catalog here, let
me just select several as and if I just click on this, you will be able to see for each
of the models, which are the languages that they support.
And then finally, I just want to show you one last thing on the quotas, go to the AWS
service and just search for quotas and just click on the service quotas and here select
bedrock, view quotas and here you can just search for let's say entropic or any model
that you are planning to use.
So here it shows cross region model inference for entropic cloud three haiku and applied
a count level quota is 100 and AWS default quotas 2000.
So in my personal account, it's much smaller number 100, but here it says that eight years
default quota values 2000, which means you can make 2000 per request to this entropic
three haiku model.
So you'll have to determine for a use case whether it meets those quota levels or not.
Okay, so that's pretty much it from this lecture.
I'll see in the next lecture.